I have been working as a UI/UX Designer at Cobone since 2011, Middle East's biggest daily deals website.

Call/Whatsapp: **+971** 50 340 3822 Email: <a href="mailto:ariflive.com@gmail.com">ariflive.com@gmail.com</a> Website: <a href="mailto:https://ariflive.com/">https://ariflive.com/</a>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariflive">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariflive</a>
Behance: <a href="https://www.behance.net/ariflive">https://www.behance.net/ariflive</a>
Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/ariflive">https://twitter.com/ariflive</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/ariflive">https://github.com/ariflive</a>

Living in: **Dubai**, **United Arab Emirates** 

Hometown: Karachi, Pakistan Birthday: September 1975

Dependents: I've wife and three kids

Speak: English & Urdu

## Skills & Work

#### UI/UX:

Photoshop • Illustrator • Sketch • XD • InVision • Flash • Dreamweaver • InDesign

### Front End:

HTML5 • SASS • CSS3 • VueJS • jQuery • JavaScript • Bootstrap • NPM • ActionScript • AJAX • JSON • XML

#### **Back End:**

PHP • MySQL • Wordpress • RESTful Services & APIs • Git • GitHub • GitLab • Apache • XAMPP • MySQL Workbench • Jenkins • FileZilla

## Others:

Jira • Visual Studio Code • Sublime Text • Search Console • A/B Testing • Analytics • Optimize

#### **Recent Work:**

Cobone - <a href="https://www.cobone.com">https://www.cobone.com</a>

ExpatWoman - https://www.expatwoman.com

EWmoda - <a href="https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmoda">https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmoda</a>
EWmums - <a href="https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmums">https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmums</a>

EWfood - <a href="https://www.expatwoman.com/ewfood">https://www.expatwoman.com/ewfood</a>

Croutique - <a href="https://www.croutique.com">https://www.croutique.com</a>

Nina Iskandar - https://www.ninaiskander.com

# **Experience**

## Cobone / UI/UX Designer

Nov 2011 - PRESENT, Dubai

- Collaborate on user experience planning with the IT Director.
- Create mockups and prototypes on tight timelines.
- Develop complex front-end UX with JavaScript, HTML5, jQuery, CSS3 and Bootstrap.
- Implement web design principles to ensure that the company website renders well across multiple devices.
- Ensure technical feasibility of UI designs.
- Maintain graphic standards and branding throughout the product's interface.
- Optimize website for maximum speed and scalability.
- Provide website maintenance and enhancements.
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies.
- Working closely with back-end developers, business analysts to define & implement amazing web-delivered user experiences.

## Media World / Senior Web Designer

Dec 2010 - Oct 2011, Dubai

- Design user interfaces to internet applications.
- Development of web applications for customer facing systems.
- Maintenance of MySQL databases for use in external and internal applications.
- Interacting with the client for requirement gathering and project reporting.
- Define site objectives by analyzing user requirements, envisioning system features and functionality.
- Develop web solutions in a variety of third party frameworks Wordpress and Drupal.
- Linux / Apache web server administration.
- Supporting, maintaining and upgrading existing live sites.

### Qatar Airways / Web Designer

Nov 2009 - Oct 2010, Doha

- Oversee day-to-day execution of email campaigns from creative setup and html coding to testing and deployment via email service provider.
- Through campaign request form management, facilitate and monitor email campaign reporting
- Ensure that the brand experience integrated into all email campaigns in a way that is consistent with overall company brand objectives.
- Manage subscriber databases, including creating and updating lists, working with database partners, and segmenting data for targeted email campaigns.
- Implement quality assurance processes to ensure accurate and on-time campaign delivery of emails.
- Contributes to the design of email campaigns and programs to those specifications.

## **Depa Ltd / Webmaster**

Apr 2008 - Nov 2009, Dubai

- Create web applications using ASP.NET, JavaScript, ActionScript and Visual Studio to increase staff effectiveness and performance.
- Ensure that the brand experience integrated into all campaigns in a way that is consistent with overall company brand objectives.
- Re-writing the web modules in ActionScript object oriented programming.
- Developing unit tests, integration tests and deployment scripts.
- Collaborate with team members to ensure web application is capable of meeting strategic aims of the core business.
- Troubleshoot and support live web applications to the end-users.
- Performing web server setup and deployment.

## Sevdotcom Ltd. / Web Designer

Jul 2006 - Apr 2008, Dubai

- Develop and maintain company websites utilizing ASP/VbScript, Actionscript, CSS, Javascript and HTML.
- Develop web applications for clients using ActionScript and Object Oriented Programming.
- Define site objectives by analyzing user requirements, envisioning system features and functionality.
- Create multimedia applications.
- Perform quality control to include link checking and visual review.
- Review web applications developed outside of the team to ensure compliance with standards.

## **Education**

## Karachi University / Bachelor of Commerce

1994 - 1996, Karachi

Petroman Training Institute / Diploma of Information Technology

1999 - 2000, Karachi

**BrainBench** / Adobe Photoshop CS3 Certification

2008, United States

# **Travelled Abroad**

Singapore • Malaysia • Thailand • Oman • Qatar • Saudi Arabia

Turkey • Georgia • Egypt • Sri Lanka • Spain • France